Veronica Shei

Front End Software Developer

veronicacshei@gmail.com 808-266-0688 github.com/veshei

SKILLS

Programming Languages

Proficient - Javascript, HTML5, CSS3 Familiar - SQL, Java, R, Python, C#, Apex

Frameworks / Libraries

NextJS, NestJS, React, React Redux, React Native, Angular, Spring Boot, .NET Core, Node.js

PROJECTS

Visa Digital Identity

Built a new digital identity web interface as part of a Mobilize for Growth project. The product interacts with a wallet payment system (i.e. Apple Pay) to verify the user's identity via the FIDO standard and returns the requested details. Built with React, React Query, Go, and MySQL.

Locate

Proof of concept that utilized Visa Checkout data to track areas of low card utilization and conducted regression analysis in R and Tableau.

Buy or Sell?

Predictive data science project with 81% accuracy to determine whether to buy or sell a stock. The project used ten years worth of S&P 500 data to conduct linear/logistic regression models and kNN models to build the predictions. The project was developed in R and SQL.

Honolulu-born, Boston-trained, New York City based. I am a front end software developer who is passionate about social good and crafting applications that elevate the user experience.

EXPERIENCE

Sunnyside - Growth Software Engineer

August 2021 - Present in New York City, NY

- Refactor pricing infrastructure in NextJS to decouple the logic from the design and increase code maintainability
- Migrated website from Squarespace to a newly coded website built in NextJS with typescript with a NestJS backend and Prismic CMS to provide both developer and business flexibility
- Upgraded Material UI version and rewired the theming and common components to support new Sunnyside design assets
- Implement product-driven growth experiments (moving email in user sign up flow, testing different homepage designs, implementing discounts, etc.) to drive up user conversion rates

Visa - Software Engineer

August 2019 - August 2021 in Austin, TX

- Fixed 50% of the backlog of components that were failing ADA a11y standards in the Visa Design System library for both React and Angular
- Led design and development for a new global value added service that will be used by issuers and business analysts for the submission and management of disputes
- Managed transition to a modular React framework in a Redux-Saga and Selector paradigm and crafted a new external portal landing page with the Visa Charts components library
- Designed 10 screens and user flows via Sketch, InVision, and the Visa Design library for external and internal portal.

OppenheimerFunds - Full Stack Software Developer

July 2018 - December 2018 in New York City, NY

- Built file drive and note editor application for iOS and Mac OS X for investment, portfolio management, and research teams of a 2000+ firm.
- Developed app in React, React Native, Spring Boot, MongoDB, Realm, and Amazon S3 as part of a 10-person team.
- Automated end to end and unit testing with Detox and Jest.

EDUCATION

Northeastern University

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science and Marketing